CURRICULUM VITAE

PERSONAL INFORMATION

Name : Septian Rizldi

Place, Date of Birth : Sampit, 6 September 1998

Domicilie : Griya Candramas Blok IO No. 33 Sidoarjo

Sex : Male Martial Status : Single

Email : <u>septianrzld17@gmail.com</u> Linkedin : linkedin.com/in/septianrizaldi



EDUCATIONAL BACKGROUND

Bachelor of Applied Science, Electric and Instrumentation Engineering (2017-2021)

Sepuluh Nopember Institute of Technology (ITS) - GPA: 3.01 of 4.00.

Final Task/ Thesis: "Design A Cost Effevtive Automatic Fish Crakcker Driver System in an Effort to IncreaseThe Production and Hygiene of Fish Crackers in Kenjeran."

ABOUT ME

When I was college, I have experience practical work in instrument and Electrical Field Operator at the PT. Perta Daya Gas and learn about Identify Documents in instrumentation such as P&ID, PFD, Instrument Hook Up, Loop diagram, Wiring Diagram, Cause and Effect Diagram, Maintenance Instrument and Basic installation and sizing field instrument. Then, I have internship in my major to design sytem air conditioning in Laboratory Computer to make a system for controlling indoor air temperature and humidity automatically to maintain indoor thermal comfort. I activated involved in the organizational academic and non-academic programs such as Staff laboratory in Control & Safety Instrument Laboratorium and I was trusted to be a Deputy Head Department Internal of BEM Faculty of Vocations and was given the responsibility of open areas of talent interest and hold forums related to the internal conditions of the Vocational Faculty. Beside that. I also participated in the big event held by BEM ITS to Welcome the arrival of new student and i was participated as cadre chori for the Instrumentation Student Association. I am familiar with simulation & Design software such as Matlab, Proteus, Psim, Autocad P&ID, Sketch-Up, and Solidworks. Then PLC Software such as CX-One and DCS Software such as Centum VP.

WORK EXPERIENCE

- Practical works or internship for 1 month at PT. Perta Daya Gas as Electrical and Instrument Field Operator, Semarang, Indonesia (June 2019 July 2019)

 Identify Documents in instrumentation such as P&ID, PED, Instrument Hook Lip, Loop
 - Identify Documents in instrumentation such as P&ID, PFD, Instrument Hook Up, Loop diagram, and Cause and Effect Diagram, Maintenace instrument and Basic installation and sizing field instrument, Identify Control System for Process gas enginee compressor. Understand the process performance of the control system in the gas enginee compressor and perform an analysis of the resulting process variables. Identify Monitoring Temperature, pressure, vibrayion for Process gas enginee compressor.
- Internship at Departement Instrumentation Engineering in Surabaya, Indonesia (September 2020-January 2021)
 - Identify the layout of the room to be controlled by the comfort conditions of the room, calculating the Cooling Load needs in each room and designing a system for controlling temperature and humidity in the room automatically to maintain thermal comfort in the room.

ORGANIZATION EXPERIENCE

- Deputy Head Department BEM Faculty of Vocations ITS (2020 – 2021)
Discussions related to the problem internal family of instrumentation engineering students as well as academic at the Department level.

- Staff of Wave Courses, Laboratory Control & Safety Departement Instrumentation (2019)
 - Composing transverse wave practicum materials and sound waves, creating a schedule of practicum activities, and evaluating practicum activities.
- Cadre Chori for The Instrumentation Student Association at Instrumentation Engineering (2019 2020)
 - Creating a plot for the formation of new student characters in accordance with the vision and mission of the association, department and institute by looking at the existing and still relevant regulations
- Mentor Group of New Student in GERIGI 2019 at Sepuluh Nopember Institute of Technology (2019)
 - Provide a good example for new students and provide direction on what is on campus by looking at the situation, organization, student activities and others as well as providing materials that are in accordance with the needs of new students

ACHIEVEMENT

- At the 2020 Electrical Competition (ELCO) with the theme "The Role of Indonesian Youth towards a Golden Indonesia Through Sustainable Development Goals 2045" At UNY as Participant. With paper "Automatic Fish Dryer Using Split AC with Heating Dehumidifier Method to Face Sustainable Development Goals (SDG'S) Towards Golden Indonesia 2045."

CERTIFICATE AND TRAINING

- Training DCS Centum VP, Yokogawa Indonesia (2021)
- Training Safety Instrumented System, Yokogawa Indonesia (2021)

ABILITY

TOOLS &	KNOWLEDGE	INTERPERSONAL				
TECHNOLOGIES	■ INSTRUMENT (P,T,F,L) &	SKILL				
☐ MS. OFFICE	SAEFTY	☐ LEADERSHIP				
□ AUTOCAD &	 ELECTRICAL WIRING 	☐ PROBLEM				
AUTOCAD P&ID	 MEASUREMENT & 	SOLVING				
□ MATLAB	CALIBRATION	□ INDONESIAN				
☐ CX-ONE	 F&G & HVAC SYSTEM 	(active)				
	 C & LADDER DIAGRAM 	☐ ENGLISH (passive)				

No 303022021000711



KEMENTERIAN PENDIDIKAN, KEBUDAYAAN, RISET, DAN TEKNOLOGI

INSTITUT TEKNOLOGI SEPULUH NOPEMBER

Terakreditasi A oleh BAN-PT, SK No. 288/SK/BAN-PT/Akred/PT/XI/2018

memberikan

Septian Rizaldi

Nomor Pokok Mahasiswa: 10511710000083 Nomor Induk Kependudukan: 3515170609980005 Lahir di Sampit, tanggal 9 Juni 1998

pada tanggal 25 Agustus 2021 telah menyelesaikan Pendidikan Sarjana Terapan (D4) Program Studi Teknologi Rekayasa Instrumentasi

(Terakreditasi Baik oleh BAN-PT, SK No. 9079/SK/BAN-PT/Akred/ST/VI/2021) berhak menyandang gelar

SARJANA TERAPAN TEKNIK (S.Tr.T.)

Diterbitkan di Surabaya pada tanggal 1 September 2021

DEKAN

Fakultas Vokasi

Prof. Ir. Muhammad Sigit Darmawan, M.Eng.Sc., Ph.D. NIP 19630726 198903 1 003

REKTOR

Prof. Dr. Ir. Mochamad Ashari, M.Eng. NIP 19651012 199003 1 003

ITS 0021018

2. TRANSKIP NILAI

INSTITUT TEKNOLOGI SEPULUH NOPEMBER TRANSKRIP / ACADEMIC TRANSCRIPT



. Kode

FACULTY OF VOCATIONAL

Pembimbing / Advisor Brian Roof (u. S.ST., M.T.

Program Studi / Study Program Nama / Name NRP / ID No Tempat, Tanggal Lahir Place, Date of Birth Gelar / Degree

Sem Kr Nilai No Kode

BANCANG BANGUN SITEM PENGERNIK KERUPUK IKAN OTOMATS HEMAT BAYA SEBAGAI UPAYA MENNIKATKAN HASU PRODUKSI DAN HECENTIA SEBUPUK IKAN DI KENJERAM DESKONA O OST FEFECTIKE AUTOMATIC FENCRACKER DINYER SYSTEM IN AMEFFORT TO INCREASE THE PRODUCTION AND HYDIENE OF FIDM CHARCKES WIN KENDERIAN

Teknologi Rekayasa Instrumentasi / Instrumentation Engineering Technology Septian Rizaldi 10511710000083 Sampit 9 Juni 1998 Sarjana Terapan Teknik (S.Tr.T.)

Indeks Prestasi / GPA : 3 01
Tahun Masuk / Entrance Year : 2017
Tahun Lulus / Graduation Year : 2021
Lema Studi / Length of Study : 8 semeeter
Predikat / Predikate : Sangat Memuaskan / Very Salisfactory
Nomor Ijazah / Diploma No : 303022021090711

Sem Kr Nital No Kode

pt Darmawari, M.Eng.Sc., Ph.D.

No	Code	Subject	Sem	· C	Grade	140	Code	Subject			Gracie		Code	Subject			Grade
-1		1 Pendidikan Agama Islam	1 1	12	A	21	VI180308	Gelombang	3	3	BC	41	VI190731		7	. 1	4 B
-	1 2114110	Reitzion						Wares					FAMILIA TO	(aternship			5
2	SK19010	1 Kimia 1	1	13	BC	22	VI180309	Termodinamika Terapon	3	13	AH	42		Proyek Athir 1	7	17	2 Aft
-	Secretorio.	Generativ I		+				Applied Thermodynamics				-		Final Project 1	A 1		1
2	TELASON	1 Fisika Terapan	1.1	1 4	BC.	23	V(180311	Elektronika Digital	3	3	8	43		Wawasan dan Apikasi Teknologi	8	- 3	3 8
2	11,14051	Applied Physics		+	1	1		Digital Electronics		201			una and	Concept of Technology	100	Т	
a	7514571	Matematika Teracan	1	14		24	VI383414	Teknolog Sensor & Transducer	94	3		44	VI190833	Parancangan Sistem Kontrol Proses	8	0 4	4 B
- 44	IF ISSCI	Applied Mathematics		+	-	100	- Tribberry	Sensor and Transducer Technology		1				De sion of Process Control Systems			
-	TC14571	Menogambar Telenk	1	12	BA	75	VIDROSTA	Sistem Pengolahan Sinyai	4	13	8	45	VI190834	Kapita Selekta Industri	- 8	3	3 B
- 51	1F-14521-	Technical Drawing	-	10	1 44	1	A) IBCATO	Signar Processing System		13				industrial Special Topics		Т	
-	wer a room	Pengantar Metrologi dan Instrumentasi	1.	1 2	EA	26	1//10/3416	Standard dan Kode	A	12	AB	45	VIII90835	Tata Tuts Karya limiah	8	1 2	7 B
.0	TF 14531	Introduction to Metrology And Instrumentation		1	100	1 50	A17.4044E	Standard and Code		1	1		-	Scientific Writing	3 5000	1	
-	WELL CO.	Teknolog Informasi dan Komunikasi	1	12	BC	22	MOROSE	Eieldromagnetik	1.4	3	C	47	VI190836	Provek Akhir 2	8	16	S AB
7	TF14531	Information and Communication Technology	- 1	14	-8-	121	AL BORTE	Electromagnetics	-	1	- 12	1	TIL SOMGO	Final Project 2		1	1
-			1.7	2	BC	100	10000410	Menggamber Instrumen	4	2	C					+	
8	TF145316	Statistik	- 1	1.6	DC.	40	VI100+13	Instrumentation Drawmos	-	+-	-	\vdash				+	
_	-	Statistics	-	2		100	1010000000	Apikasi Teknologi Cerdas	1	3	AB	\vdash				+	1
9	UG18091	Behasa Indonesia	- 4	12	A	29	4819.904	Smart Technology Application	-	3	AG	\vdash				+	
100		Indonesian	-	13	AB	-	LIMORE DO	Pemrograman Mirrokantroler	-	4	В	\vdash				+	1
10	IG14110:	Wakasan Kebangsaan	- 2	13	AD	30	A1130250	Microcontroller Programming	-	17		\vdash				+	1
		Divids	-	1.	-	1		Teknik Otomasi	- 6	1 2	В	\vdash				+	+
11	(G141108	Bahasa koggra	12	-3	B	30	V1190521	Automation Engineering	-	1.3	- 0	\vdash	-			+	
200	Callenger	English	-	-	-	-	1000000000		17	100	В	*	-			+	+
12	TF145321	Pervograman Komputer	1.2	3	BC	32	VI190522	Perpendahan Panas	2	3	8	*			_	+	+
		Computer Programming		-	-	-				3	-	X				+	1
13	TF145322	Sistem Pneumatik dan Hidrolik	2	3	A.B.	33	VI190524	Sistem Konversi Daya Listrik	5	3	В	\vdash			_	+	-
956	Name of the last	Presumetics And Hidrautics System						Electric Power Conversion Systems								+	-
14	TF145323	Rangkaran Listrik	2	3	C	34	VI160526	Teknik Perawatan dan Perbaikan	5	2	C					+	-
		Electric Oircurat	177.00		-			Maintenance and Repair Techniques		240	- 3		- 3			+	-
15	TF145324	Teknik Pengukuran dan Kalibrasi	2	3	H	35		Teknopieneur	5	2	AB					+	-
	D. Common	Measurement And Calibration Techniques		L				Technopreneurship	A							+	-
16	VI180203	Matematika Terapah	2	3	В	36		Engineering Commissioning	6	3	AB	\Box				+	-
	-	Applied Mathematics	The state of the s		10000	PA.		Engineering Commissioning		100						-	-
17	VI180205	Elektroniko Analog	2	3	AB	37		Sistem Terranam	6	3	8		1			4	-
- 0		Analog Electronics	200		0.00			Emberded System								-	
18 0	V:190205	Texnik Karltrasi	2	3	AB	35	Vr19052B		6	2	AB						
1	minute state of the later	Galibration Techniques	77.5		12000			HSEQ	- 1000		1000						
19	UG191913	Kewarganegereen	3	2	C	39	Vi190629	Sixtem Kontrol Terdistribusi	6	3	'AB						
		Codes		r	11105			Distributed Control System			1		The state of				
20	V/180307	Dinamika Sittem	3	3	AE	40	VI190630	Sistem instrumentasi Industri	6	3	В						
1		System Dynamics	-		1000	133		Industrial Instrumentation System		6.5	-			The Paris Contract of			
\rightarrow		200.000	_					The state of the s			1			Aumlah Kredit / Total of Credits	14	15	

3. SERTIFIKAT GERIGI 2019



4. SERTIFIKAT YOKOGAWA INDONESIA

YOKOGAWA

Certificate
OF APPRECIATION

In appreciation of your attendance to the training
Safety Instrumented System Appreciation

Conducted by PT. Yokogawa Indonesia, Plaza Oleos
August 9, 2021

Arsil Ardhy
Trainer

Embun Marintan
Training Center Lead

REF. NO : TRC21-VIII-494



Certificate OF APPRECIATION

Septian Rizaldi

In appreciation of your attendance to the training Centum VP Basic Operation & Basic Engineering

Conducted by PT. Yokogawa Indonesia, Plaza Oleos August 10 & 12, 2021

Desya Prinka Khoirun Nisa

Trainer

Embun Marintan Training Center Lead

5. SERTIFIKAT ORGANIZATION















NRP: 10511710000062

Diberikan Kepada

Septian Rizaldi

Sebagai Koordinator Steering Committee Pendidikan Orientasi Dini Mahasiswa Teknik Instrumentasi HIMATEKINS ITS

NRP 105117 10000 010

23 Februari - 30 November 2020 Di Institut Teknologi Sepuluh Nopember, Surabaya Departemen Ketua Pelaksana Ketua HIMATEKINS ITS urpentasi-ITS akhmao Amrinsya B M. Nidhommuddin





6. SERTIFIKAT PENGGANTI MAGANG



7. SERTIFIKAT TOEFL

